## **JOHN A. ROBLES PEREZ**

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly technical SW Engineer who excels in providing efficient with design, analysis, development, deployment, and documentation for project ranging from SW, application and platform engineering. Possess experience in both in back-end and front-end programming utilizing XML, JSON, Java, Maven, Spring Boot, SFTP protocol, AWS, APIs, and MS SQL Server. Able structure, design and build Full Stack Applications, install applications onto servers and offer L1-3 technical support engineering in addition to troubleshooting performs tests and updates. Develop solutions interfacing with client and internal systems, applications, SW and platforms using XML and JSON and communicate with all levels of an organization in English and Spanish.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# The Cervantes Group, Inc., San Juan, PR SW Engineer

### Aug 2022 - Present

- Develop solutions for file transfers (inbound/outbound traffic) interfacing with client and internal systems, applications, SW and platforms using XML and JSON.
- Participate in the full Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including requirements gathering, documentation, coding/execution, code review/testing, implementation and reports creation.
- Develop solutions with JavaScript, PHP and Ninja JS for Microjuris Application for customer named Centrix participating in all phases of the Agile Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- Generate reports with JasperReports, an open-source tool which allows to write and edit report in Sodalis Application while creating and configuring API's in Unify Application.
- Create and develop Transaction Request API's (Payment Gateway).
- Meet with cross-functional teams to gather and document project and client requirements.

# **Health Computer Systems, Inc.,** San Juan, PR **Developer**

Nov 2021 - Aug 2022

- Designed, analyzed, documented, and deployed applications utilizing XML, JSON, Java, Maven, Spring Boot, SFTP protocol, AWS, and MS SQL Server.
- Developed file sharing, sending and transfer solutions interfacing with client and internal systems, applications, SW and platforms using XML and JSON.
- Performed tests and updates within XML, JSON environments in addition to gathering requirements and producing documentation with instructions for execution of coding solutions, design and layouts for application
- Managed and maintained Windows Server and SW written in Java, Maven, XML, JSON offering technical support engineering L1-3.
- Updated Technical User Manuals and created and managed API configurations.
- Managed customer technical support system called GoToAssist in which through tickets it contains their needs or doubts about our system or issues related.

# Watric Company, Mayaguez, PR

### Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

# **Intern Web Developer**

- Fix the server bugs for the website. Update and added new information in some pages for new incoming products, about to drop in the market.
- Analyze and developed a program based in Mathematical calculus for measuring air filtration
- Generated frontend and cloud solutions: Windows 10, Apache, PHP, HTML, CSS, Heroku, HostGator.

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **Education:**

- University of Puerto Rico, Mayaguez
  - o Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering (May 2022)

#### **Certifications:**

- Advanced CSS and Sass Udemy Academy (March 2023)
- Introduction to Business Data Analysis Udemy Academy (March 2023)
- Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS Udemy Academy (March 2023)
- JavaScript Course Udemy Academy (December 2022)
- Practical Ethical Hacking Udemy Academy (August 2020)
- SQL Basic Concept and Techniques UPRM (May 2020)
- Cybersecurity Basic Concept and Techniques UPRM (May 2020)
- React Native The Practical Guide Udemy Academy (June 2019)
- Python Masterclass Udemy Academy (January 2019)

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JSON, SOAP, PHP, NodeJS, XML, Java, React.js, Python, JavaScript, React Native, Git/GitHub, HTML5, (S)CSS3, AWS, APIs, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Heroku, jQuery, JSX, Vite.js, Maven, Docker, MS Excel

### **CONTACT INFO**

Phone Number: 787-460-6052

Email: j\_robles0717@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-andrew-robles-perez-b1a85a106/